<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Pry's Blog</title>
 <link href="prydt.xyz/b/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="prydt.xyz/b/"/>
 <updated>2020-07-12T12:43:14-05:00</updated>
 <id>prydt.xyz</id>
 <author>
   <name>Pranoy Dutta</name>
   <email>pranoydll@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Breakfast of Champions Review</title>
   <link href="prydt.xyz/b/2020/07/12/breakfast-of-champions.html"/>
   <updated>2020-07-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>prydt.xyz/2020/07/12/breakfast-of-champions</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I haven’t been reading much lately.
But I did finish Breakfast of Champions by Kurt Vonnegut finally and it was an interesting novel.
I’ve been a fan of his work for a while already and loved Slaughterhouse Five and The Sirens of Titan both of which were unconventional sci-fi stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breakfast of Champions on the other hand is a more down to Earth novel but still has many distinct qualities of Vonnegut’s writing peppered in.
The story revolves around Kilgore Trout (a sci-fi author) and as such is jam packed with 1-page descriptions of books that Trout had written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story focuses on the build up of a single event: a mentally ill man finally snaps because of a solipsistic Trout novel and goes on a rampage.
It is less about the event but about the surrounding characters and their environment; Vonnegut describes the local high schools in the area, the adult correction facility which many African Americans and “gays” are sent to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vonnegut describes American in its glory and folly, a land of freedom and opportunity for some. The most sad thing about the novel is that while the novel was published in 1973, all of Vonnegut’s criticisms of America hold true more than ever. Racism, sexism, and inequality are all still large problems that need fixing in 2020. Overall I would say the satrical and witty comedy is worth a read and still ends with a touch of hope as it shows that even a single person (Kilgore Trout in this case), can cause change in magnitudes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rating: 7/10, not my favorite Vonnegut book but definitely worth your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– pry&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Installing the Spike RISC-V Simulator</title>
   <link href="prydt.xyz/b/2020/06/16/installing-spike.html"/>
   <updated>2020-06-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>prydt.xyz/2020/06/16/installing-spike</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spike is a RISC-V Simulator. Here are the steps to installing Spike from source for 32bit simulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dependencies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Device Tree Compiler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-commandline&quot;&gt;# Arch Linux
sudo pacman -S dtc

# Ubuntu / Debian
sudo apt install device-tree-compiler
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing Spike&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make a new directory for Spike&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir RISCV
cd RISCV
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clone the repos for the RISCV GNU toolchain, proxy kernel (pk), and Spike itself&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone --recursive https://github.com/riscv/riscv-gnu-toolchain
git clone https://github.com/riscv/riscv-pk
git clone https://github.com/riscv/riscv-isa-sim
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set environment variables (preferably move these commands into bashrc, zshrc, or something similar)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;export RISCV=/path/from/home/to/RISCV
export PATH=$PATH:$RISCV/bin
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build the toolchain (this will take a while so make some tea or something)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd riscv-gnu-toolchain
mkdir build
cd build
../configure --prefix=$RISCV --with-arch=rv32i
make
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, to build the Proxy Kernel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd ../riscv-pk
mkdir build
cd build
../configure --prefix=$RISCV --host=riscv32-unknown-elf
make
make install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally to build Spike&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd ../riscv-isa-sim
mkdir build
cd build
../configure --prefix=$RISCV --enable-histogram
make
make install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are done!! To test if your install is working correctly use the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;riscv32-unknown-elf-gcc helloworld.c # where helloworld.c is any C program
RISCV/riscv-isa-sim/build/spike --isa=RV32IMAC RISCV/riscv-pk/build/pk a.out
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Introductions | Making a Blog!</title>
   <link href="prydt.xyz/b/2020/05/31/making-a-blog.html"/>
   <updated>2020-05-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>prydt.xyz/2020/05/31/making-a-blog</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m committing to writing a blog. This may or may not be my 3rd attempt and I’m just going to go and stick with it. I think that’s the best course of action. Previously, I was too caught up with what static site generator to use or exactly what to post and this time I’m just sticking with something basic and will continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My set up for blogging is rather simple. I’m using &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; which is not the newest or flashiest static site generator but it gets the job done. The theme I am using is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ronv/sidey&quot;&gt;Sidey&lt;/a&gt; and I personally think it looks amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose that’s it for now. This is just the first post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– pry&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
